

Athul J R

student

🗷 athulkarthik20@gmail.com 📞 7560914142 👂 kollam,kerala

indian https://athul-20.github.io/portfolio.github.io/ in linkedin/athul

github.com/Athul-20

PROFILE

Athul J R, a dedicated student with a passion for digital innovation and social well-being, showcases a portfolio of projects that demonstrate my skills in digital media and community engagement. Committed to personal and professional growth, my resume highlights my experience in project management and critical skill development, ready to contribute to impactful initiatives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2023 - 08/2023 **KERALA INFORMATION CENTER**

Web content manager

Educational institutions and online Faculty management in kerala university.

02/2023 - 05/2023 intern at ICFOSS

Applications developer

- Developed and implemented the "Conference Management System" during the internship period.
- Collaborated with a team to ensure timely completion of project milestones. Accomplishments:
- Successfully delivered the project within the internship period (01/02/2023 to 19/05/2023).
- Gained practical experience in software development and teamwork in a professional setting.

EDUCATION

08/2023 – present Post graduation in Computer science with specialization in AI

University of Kerala

08/2020 - 03/2023 Bachelors in computer science

University of Kerala percenteage -77

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, R, SQL
- Data Analysis: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Project Management
- Machine Learning: Supervised/Unsupervised Learning, CNN, RNN, LSTM
- Natural Language Processing: NLTK, spaCy, Hugging Face
- Problem Solving and critical thinking for AI
- Deep Learning Frameworks: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikitlearn
- Natural Language Processing: NLTK, spaCy, Hugging Face
- computer vision :OpenCv

Malayalam Hindi LANGUAGES English Tamil

AWARDS

Chief Minister's Shield Competition Directorate of Higher secondary education **♂** INTERESTS **Artificial Intelligence** Machine Learning, and Ethical Data Science, and NLP AI. • Computer Vision and Generative AI. • AI Applications in Healthcare and Smart Cities. • Sustainable AI and Technology for Social Good. **CERTIFICATES** • internship certificate by • certification of appreciation ☑ • National cadet corps "c" ICFOSS ☑ certicificate

PROJECTS

Conference management system

Hand written recognition model

Water reservoir capacity prediction using regression models

Multiclass skin lession classification using Mobilenet-V2

COURSES

Data Science for Engineers

NPTEL, IIT madras

Python programming

Great Learning

Python for Machine learning 🖸

Great learning

Front end Developer-HTML

Great Learning

ORGANIZATIONS

District Administration Pathanamthitta

Volunteer

Kerala State Blood Trasfusion Council

lead of adult blood donation campaign